# COLIN GROARK

## WEB DEVELOPER

Full-stack web developer with experience building responsive websites and developing efficient systems and tools in the private and non-profit sectors. I have a firm grasp on Git version control, RESTful APIs, and technologies from React and JavaScript to PostgreSQL and Node. Prior to engineering, I worked for consulting firms and non-profits where I garnered experience managing programs, teams, budgets and business development processes.

### CONTACT

www.colingroark.com

**♀** Seattle, Washington

in colin-groark/

n cgroark

### EDUCATION

### General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Training 2018

### University of Washington, Evans School of **Public Policy and Governance**

MPA: Environmental Policy and Natural Resource Management

Certificate: Environmental Management

### **Trinity College**

BA: International Studies, Hispanic Studies

### SKILLS

### Front End Web Development: React,

JavaScript, JQuery, ES6, CSS3, HTML5, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, Recharts

### Back End Web Development: Node.js.

PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Python, MongoDB, Django

### Technology: RESTful API,

Heroku Cloud Platform, Git Workflow, GitHub,

Languages: Advanced Spanish, Beginning Swahili and Japanese

### VOLUNTEERING

## Seattle Public Utilities: Solid Waste Seattle

Advisory Committee Committee Member Nov 2016 to Current

Seattle Tilth Alliance Master Composter/Soil Builder Apr 2016 to Volunteer

### RECENT PROJECTS

### Node.js/Express: Carbon Commuter

Track, log and chart carbon emissions of trips travelled based on distance and mode of transport

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Google Maps API, Chart.js, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Data visualizations for distance ratios and carbon emissions using Chart, is JavaScript library
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://carbon-commute.herokuapp.com/

### React/MongoDB: HouseHub

Create a house profile with roommates. Post memos, assign and track chores, house bills, and pantry items

- Technologies: React, MongoDB, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://tpcc.herokuapp.com/

#### Node.js/Express: Get Out There

Search for National Parks by state, save your favorite parks, see location and real-time weather forecast

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- RESTful APIs: National Park Service, Google Maps, Weather Underground
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://get-out-there-parksweather.herokuapp.com/

### **EXPERIENCE**

### General Assembly

Full-Stack Web Development Student

Seattle, Washington Nov 2017 to Feb 2018

- 12-week immersive full-stack web development training with 480 hours of instruction
- Built responsive user-focused projects drawing on technologies that include React, Express, Node, PostreSQL, JQuery, JavaScript, HTML 5, CSS 3, Mocha and Chai for unit testing, and front-end libraries and frameworks such as Materialize, Bootstrap, CSS Grid, Recharts and Chart.js
- Established firm grasp of RESTful API architecture, data visualization JavaScript libraries, Heroku cloud platform, JSON, AJAX, Git and GitHub version control, database structure and modeling, and emerging web development trends
- Worked with cross-functional, agile teams of developers and UX designers to bring week-long and quick turnaround projects to fruition using team management software such as Trello

### Tilth Alliance (Seattle Tilth)

Director, Community Education and Environmental Programs

Seattle, Washington Aug 2015 to Nov 2017

- Oversaw Tilth Alliance portfolio of resource conservation and stewardship education programs
- Managed \$500K annual contract with Seattle Public Utilities on resource conservation and stormwater management, working closely with City of Seattle managers to ensure my team met all deliverables and stayed within contractual budget
- Managed 11 person team and \$890K grant and contract portfolio that funded seven core programs
- Built budget tracking systems in Excel to monitor program expenditures; and SharePoint metrics tracker to monitor program
- Developed processes and used Asana program management software to track program deliverables, grant applications and
- Led proposal strategy and client interview to secure 5-year \$2.2 million contract with Seattle Public Utilities

Envirolssues Business Development Associate

Seattle, Washington Apr 2013 to Aug 2015

- Managed business development and marketing team for community outreach consulting firm, maintaining win rate above
- Led proposal teams of technical senior-staff and supported strategy to compete for hundreds of public infrastructure projects across Washington Oregon, Idaho, California and Colorado
- Created metrics dashboard and data analysis tools in Excel to allow for simple reporting on tracking and assessing proposal trends
- Worked with engineering team to build out business development side of in-house EnviroLytical software to store all proposal data
- Developed training materials and led all staff trainings on marketing and business development best practices

### Basel Action Network

Research Intern

Seattle, Washington Apr 2012 to Mar 2013

- Conducted research and drafted reports on the illegal trafficking of electronic waste
- Led investigative team in Los Angeles to identify suspicious recyclers and embed tracking devices to assess illegal export
- Developed data calculator for iOS app to measure environmental benefits of recycling electronics

Management Systems International Business Development Associate and Consultant

Washington, DC Aug 2007 to Sep 2011

- Coordinated proposal teams of technical senior-staff to compete for foreign aid projects up to \$21million across seven sectors
- Ensured RFP compliance and on-time delivery of polished proposals around the world within strict deadlines
- Provided budgetary, recruitment and report-writing support for complex international aid contract proposals